Justin B. Helfman

Denver, CO 80206

440-465-9588 | justinbhelfman@gmail.com | https://jbhelf.github.io | www.linkedin.com/in/justin-b-helfman/

SUMMARY

Motivated and results-driven DevOps engineer experienced in establishing and improving code infrastructure. Well-versed in software development with many data science/ML side projects. Enthusiastic about continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD), cloud computing, and enabling people to succeed. **Relevant skills:**

Azure Fundamentals (certification) • C • Python • Git/Gitlab • PowerShell • SQL • YAML • Terraform Linux/Unix • CI/CD • AWS • Google Cloud Platform • Azure • Tensorflow & PyTorch • Kubernetes

WORK EXPERIENCE

Alteryx, Broomfield, CO - Associate Site Reliability Engineer

July 2022 - January 2023

Oversaw cloud operations efforts, resolving urgent defects and system outages affecting customers

- Directed SRE into an agile-based workflow, resulting in 29 documented and completed epics in 3 months
- Orchestrated design of automated auditing tools for Security and Organizational Controls (SOC 2)

Alteryx, Broomfield, CO - DevOps Intern

May - August 2021

Built Amazon Machine Images (AMI) to expand data sources used with Alteryx Designer

- EC2 AMIs used in over 130,000 instances in GitLab pipelines over a 12-week period
- Built a framework to automatically audit AMIs and determine value based on accessibility and security

Eaton Corporation, Moon, PA— Software Engineering Intern

January - April 2021

Created remote scripts to interface with circuit breakers, testing for functionality and defects

Architected automated firmware testing pipelines, allowing developers to focus solely on feature design

Eaton Corporation, Plymouth, MN – Software Engineering Intern

June - August 2020

Organized and delivered a continuous integration/continuous development tool using virtual machines

Presented project summary, saving developers an estimated 2,000 hours per year

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN - Teaching Assistant

January - May 2022

Created coursework for students to gain experience in CI/CD topics using GitHub actions

Course topics included CI/CD, IaaS, PaaS, FaaS, Python, NodeJs, UNIX, GIT, JIRA, and Fuzzing

Alpha Epsilon Pi, West Lafayette, IN – Recruitment Chair

January 2019 - November 2020

Orchestrated recruitment team, conducted recruiting planning and efforts

- Recruited a new member class, exceeding previous records by 35% in my first year
- Designed socially distant events during COVID increasing membership in my second year by 16%

EDUCATION

Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN

August 2018 - May 2022

• B.S. Computer Engineering

GPA: 3.14/4.00

• Entrepreneurship & Innovation Certificate

PROJECTS

NHL Score Prediction Neural Network

December 2022

Designed a multilayer perceptron neural network that predicts NHL game outcomes

Digital Systems Design Project

August - December 2021

Created an app to digitally record and display the results of a real chess game

Worked with chess AI to aid player moves, and provide a variable-difficulty computer to compete against

Deep Learning (Neural Networks) Design Projects

August - December 2020

Implemented Neural Turing Machines, Convolutional LSTM, and Generative Adversarial Networks

SARS-CoV-2 (COVID-19) Analyses

May - December 2020

- Compiled a review and method validation of 4 ICML papers in the context of infectious disease forecasting
- Administered predictive mortality and infection models and observed trends between these forecasts and global ratings by country of human development, free press, and mean years of schooling